called the regular scheduled meeting of my city council for Monday, November 20th, 2023.
Two public input on scheduled personal appearances, having none, three claims list.
This was the one that I was asking you about, wasn't it, Bo?
Were these side by side, they were grants or donations, I'm sorry?
Yes, it was from this was the chair key.
Yeah.
Okay.
So, how come they're on the here as a...
Those two approve?
Thank you.
Hi.
Hello.
Four.
November 6th, 2023.
Regular meeting.
Meeting minutes.
Motion.
Say.
Hello.
Hi.
Five buzz amendment.
This is it right here in it.
I'm a number 24 to zero seven, receiving a 50,000 dollar chair key trial.
A travel grant for police, emergency management and police communications and increasing the
ARPA street repair budget to spend the entire two million, two hundred and
nine six thousand, seven hundred and twenty-four dollars and twenty-three.
We're portable ARPA funds and receiving,
the two hundred thousand Ottawa County ARPA grant monies for park.
So, we received a lot of money.
Yeah, that 50,000 that's on there was 50,000 for police, 50,000 for emergency
management and 50,000 for communications individually, totaling 150,000 in Cherokee.
What's the most dangerous structure to 270 dollars?
So, there was like a map there or something.
We didn't budget the full amount.
We received the second half of our the city received ARPA monies during COVID and we received the second half
last year and not the full amount was budgeted to buy two hundred and seventy dollars.
So, we're just making it right.
So, the full amount, most of it is going to rather pair, but two hundred and fifty is going
to water winding policemen.
And then the last one is the parks received two hundred,000 of Ottawa County ARPA money
to install a portable HVAC system and to execute.
We received it and experimented.
How do they, how do they install a room portable?
It still has to be ventured.
Yes, yes.
You have a plugin in.
Any nodes on it?
Say you install that at that building,
but the actual age bag you can move it to some other place.
If you want to, yeah, they're actual.
So we've gone really full circle on this.
From working with the county extensively to making sure
that if we were going to mount specific units there
that we had a amount of opin' off, and then by the time we figured
out how to mount them, we're going to have to mount them
pretty much roof height to keep them out of the water, and then it was, well maybe we could
mount them on a trailer, then the trailer could be moving, but after going full circle
in that we came back around and said, can't we just buy portable units so that they could
be used not only out there when needed, because they wouldn't be used very often because
we're not going to leave them all all the time. Pay the electricity on that. Only when there's an
event that somebody wants to pay the electricity on run in them. So everybody decided it was better
to have these portable units that we could use out there, but in the event we had a reason
to use them here at City Hall, but we could. We had a system fail or something like that. So
County agreed, everybody agreed just to let Kevin spend the money on the units that he needed
for these portals. So he's really excited to have these portable units that we can cool the
expo as well as use somewhere else if we need it. Well there'd be something we could like do a tent at
the best. Yes. And we're going to cool it down. Yes, they are. We can get electric to them, Tyler,
and then we can. They obviously can get pull some electric because they're large, but yes. Kevin
actually talked about that. Motion to approve. Second. Hi.
Hi. Hi. How are you? Hi.
Hi. Hi. Part six, Dr. Track. Contract to track policies. Stay in it operating procedure to provide public access
to policies and provide internal attestation, internal for me. I'm training not to exceed
5,663 dollars. It's on this agenda because the city side will be using it all. The funds are coming
from the MSUA, but the city. Motion to approve. Hi. Hi. Hi.
Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Part six.
Hi. Part six. Hi. Part seven. Resolution 3023-13 for bridge inspection responsibility by the city of
Mio for compliance with national bridge inspection standards, utilize an option number three to use the same
firm, the county, selects. Yes. So this is for your contract with the guy engineering, the same engineering,
the county uses to inspect the city bridges. So there's no cost to the city. This is paid for by the
federal government. They would provide us a report. We're sending it at the meeting if you'd like.
So we pay nothing, but we get results. Yeah. Yeah. So they produce a report to us and just say this,
so we need to be fixed, you know, this is what it does.
Yeah, it's pretty good deal, we can afford it, most of you approve, take Williams, hi.
Hi, thank you.
Resolution 2020-3-14, cutification of the city of Mayan, Oklahoma Code of Wardensis, can include
2017.
So twice a year, a unit code that rates are code with this sub enough.
This is 2017.
This is just officially recognizing.
And then the store code that brings this up to date.
Motion to approve.
Sorry.
Hi.
Hello.
Williams.
Hi.
Other new business of any of which is the residents of the post in this agenda.
Can't staff report.
11 mayor, council, community announcement.
What a great weekend.
Good night.
Saturday morning.
There's a great to see all those people in the businesses too.
Not just out on the sidewalk.
People actually in the businesses.
After dark.
That was really cool.
Well, I guess dark at or four clock now.
Well, yeah, I get that, but still.
They were in their well after dark.
I mean, I didn't leave till like about seven or seven,
seven, thirty, and there were still people.
After dark in these places that wouldn't otherwise been.
So good for the people that were down there that got the extra revenue.
And hopefully this is something that we can keep going.
If you want anything nice to say.
I'll say anything at all.
Hello.
I'm going to a pile on the Brian here.
Put a great event downtown.
It was good to see families down there enjoying themselves.
Kids laughing and playing.
And then the snow machine, the rain there.
I mean, it was and seeing the light.
That's when we hung in over my street.
It was just really cool.
And the great thing for me about it was it was a team effort.
Everybody was a ball.
Childish here is a ball.
Kevin's here is a ball.
HT's guys are involved.
Everybody is involved.
And whenever we're rolling the same direction and pulling the same way.
Man, we can do anything.
And I had so many people call me.
Call me.
Text me.
Message me.
Stop me in person.
And thank me for this event.
But I think we all understand this is a team.
And it took everybody to pull it off.
I know the vendors upstairs.
But one lady sold out in a hour.
The first hour she sold out.
But the other vendors said they did more on Friday night than they did.
the two nights the year before. So that was good. Good fellas Bobby said that he had his biggest
night ever in my, since he's been in my own five years, he had his biggest night ever. So he was
really happy about that. I don't know, the donkeys didn't really did well. While the this is down
down did well, but really good event. And you know, Keesha did a great job trying to grow, did a great
job, all their support, the great job. Santa was there and others lying for him. The first night,
Friday night there was a line of 152 people waiting to get in. I know Saturday there was another line,
not quite that long, but there was still a line that next morning. So the community's energized
for Christmas. So we just need to keep that rolling. Another tree showed up today in town history,
got it set, let it rest or relax or whatever it's called. There you go. But it's set. So I think after
everything's giving you guys a little bit busy on it and down down, start getting transformed. All the
windows look great. There's just, there's a big effort going on forever body. And for me, I just
appreciate it. I appreciate everybody's efforts. It's just paying off with the energy to communities
but back. So what's the feasibility next year closing down the street to keep traffic out? Actually,
I did Dr. Keesha this morning. I stopped by just to thank her for her efforts this weekend. And she said
that I think they want to shut that block off just for safety because it was kids running back and forth.
And the traffic was backed up. But it was cool to see all the traffic. But I know Friday I was still
at work for that first hour. And I had a guy on the phone. And he's like, I don't want to
catch going on a mile or I can get through here. And so it was great. It was great because he was
backed up traffic because everybody was trying to get down there. And I don't know what the total number
was of people or anything else. But I know it was better than then we've had down in a long time.
So I'd like to say there's many, many people thanking me. But that's passed on to everybody.
Because it was just good. It's going to be a second heritage festival. If it continues to grow,
I mean, okay. No. Well, and then you know the tree lot is coming up on the first. So I'm
another bit down there for that. I know that several of our team mates have been working on that as well.
And then we've got the parade on the second. And the ball will be hanging out on the collar and this
Christmas work will call me in. You'll thank Bill Osborne for that. He missed family pain for that.
The fundraiser has been started for Christmas decorations. So they're going to raise funds to
try to bring back better and more Christmas decorations for downtown. Thanks to Jennifer and Bo and
everybody that worked on getting that set up. But that's taken off. So I don't know who's on the
absolutely. So it's exciting. It's a great time of year. I mean, it's going to be busy from here to the
year. I mean, you think about all the things that's going on at the Coleman in a main street.
It's going to be great, so hopefully everybody will keep showing up, coming to the parade, coming to the tree lighting, going to all the, you know,
that's going on at the theater, that we have an opportunity for just a spectacular Christmas season.
Hey, Balsai, anything?
All right, let's go to 12.
See, man, you know.
Well, I just kind of, on the tail end of that, to celebrate all the activity around the CBBE and birds and all that,
but unfortunately we're saying goodbye to me and a Davis.
I'm just going to be leaving this.
But in that same breath, we want to congratulate her with all that we can.
She is accepting a fantastic position as a president of the Grove Area Chamber of Commerce.
And I know she's really excited.
This is a big position for her.
She's been with my mother six, two years in service, the director of my mother CBBE, the Convention of Visitors Bureau.
She also serves on a lot of board associations around town,
and is currently the chair of the Oklahoma Travel, the Travel Industry Association.
She has been an absolute tremendous asset to me who didn't have myself the experience of tourism.
And so I've been able to lean on her a lot, but she provides a lot of input and guidance to a lot of people in the community around tourism and event planning.
And so she will be greatly missed.
And she and I had a great conversation.
Last Friday, when she came and talked to me, we spent well over an hour, not only, you know, just kind of going through what she's doing.
And her telling me all about her opportunity and growth and her excitement there.
But kind of brainstorming and collaborating on how we move forward.
And I really feel like what we're gaining is a peer and growth to help bring our communities together to raise all ships.
And so her ability now to work closely in the chamber and economic development of growth.
She'll be working with Shayna Duhon.
Of our my academic development service.
I know those two are very tight already and so they'll be working closely together.
And so we have a great relationship with leadership of growth, but this will give us an opportunity to even tighten that and really work together on what we can do together.
So we're certainly excited for her.
I think it just shows us what we can all do once again if we work together here locally, but as a region.
I've been asking a lot about her position and right now she and I did spend a lot of time talking about the position and how it's grown since I've been here.
And so she had a lot of recommendations of things that could possibly be done that I want to look at that entire group.
They just do an amazing job. We saw that this weekend.
I want to make sure that we set them up for success going forward.
And so I'll be looking at that entire work chart from tourism and CVB to MDRA.
Everything that's going on with the Coleman and how we can you know best organize them.
Organizationally and financially and with the right leader in there.
So I'll be combining probably some duties and responsibilities or breaking out some other ones
that she had some recommendations on.
So I think there's an opportunity to really evaluate that job description before we put
it out.
But my goal is to post that publicly and see what kind of attention we could get.
I think with everything going on in my Emma, with everything going on in this region, with
a theme park, it's possible we could really get some heavy hitters that want to come
help my Emma achieve some big things in this area.
So I think it's wise for us to put it out and see who wants to come help us and of course
we've got lots of folks internally that may want to apply.
So we'll be looking at all options in evaluating everything.
I talked a lot with Amanda about the interim.
She's going to be helping us for the next several weeks.
I'll be meeting with her and staff next week to kind of start really framing a foundation
of what we're going to do as an intern.
I'll probably need to appoint somebody as an intern that's came up.
People have been asking me, but of course, if necessary, I can appoint an intern in that
role until we find somebody to replace her.
So somebody will have some really big shoes to fill, but luckily she'll be, she'll be working
with us from here on out.
She's never more than a phone call away and so I'm just really proud of her and all that she's
done here and all the great things on who she's going to go do for that period and grow.
So I just wanted to make everybody aware of that and wish her all the best.
So we got thirteen adjourned.
Some rooms.
Okay.
All right.
Bye.